MARK WANG

STUDENT AT BAYVIEW SECONDARY SCHOOL

+1 647-765-2772

Q Greater Toronto Area, Canada

imtheryzon@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Passionate and curious student interested in various areas in the Computer Science discipline. Profound experience in Back-End Web Development, Algorithms and Data Structures, Cybersecurity, and programming languages such as Python, Java, C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, and C#. Organized, open-minded, creative, and reliable individual that thrives both alone and in a team setting.

<u>LinkedIn:</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-wang-364b14269/

EDUCATION

Bayview Secondary School

High School Diploma

2020 - 2024

4.0 GPA

EXPERTISE

Algorithms & Data Structures

Back-End Web Development

Cybersecurity

Software Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Founder and President

Sep 2022 - Present

Bayview Cyber Security Club

Founder and President of Bayview Cyber Security Club, a club that aims to educate, challenge, and inspire the next generation of cybersecurity enthusiasts. Helped manage logistics, created educational content, prepared numerous club events and activities, and built and maintained the club's CTF online judge website.

Founder and President

Apr 2023 - Present

CyberNova Collective

President and Founder of CyberNova, a non-profit organization dedicated to giving individuals an efficient medium to host various STEM competitions as well as providing numerous programs, courses, and educational content. Helped manage logistics, create courses/programs, prepare organizational events, and outreach.

Vice President

Jun 2023 - Present

Bayview Computer Club

Vice President of Bayview Computer Club, one of the biggest clubs in Bayview Secondary School. Bayview Computer Club strives to educate high school students in various areas of Computer Science such as web development, game development, machine learning, competitive programming, etc.

ACTIVITIES & AWARDS

STEM Tutor

Bayview Secondary School

Tutored high school students in Computer Science, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, and Mathematics

2023 CCC Senior Honour Roll

University of Waterloo

Achieved a 41/75 score in the 2023 Canadian Competition Senior Division, placing in the top 5% of all participants.

USACO Silver Division

USA Computing Olympiad

Achieved silver division in the United States of America Computing Olympiad.



Java and C/C++ Teacher

Jun 2023 - Present

Code 4 Tomorrow

Taught the advanced Java curriculum as well as C/C++ at Code 4 Tomorrow. Code 4 Tomorrow is a non-profit organization based in San Jose, California, United States, that gives free computer science education to thousands of students of all ages and backgrounds worldwide.

Java Instructor

Jan 2022 - Present

STEM of Tomorrow

Java Instructor for STEM of Tomorrow, a non-profit organization that aims to give every individual free STEM education, regardless of their location or background. Helped create and teach Java courses, which helps educate students of all levels about the programming language as well as object-oriented programming.

Science Unlimited

University of Toronto

Participated in the Science Unlimited summer program. Science Unlimited gives high school students the opportunity to engage themselves in various workshops from the Departments of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Chemistry, Computer Science, Earth Sciences, Math, Physics and the School of the Environment.

PROJECTS

Bayview CTF Website

Sep 2022 - Present

BCTF is an open-source online judge designed to host Capture the Flag (CTF) competitions as well as cybersecurity-related problems. It aims to challenge curious and passionate individuals of all levels in the Information Technology sector. As a back-end developer, I contributed to building, creating, and maintaining the website.

Coursuccess

Mar 2023 - Apr 2023

Coursuccess is a course selection and grade-viewing website that aids high school students in choosing their courses for an upcoming semester. Coursuccess uses a complex algorithm that automatically generates a timetable that suits a student based on their interests and target career paths. Additionally, with the integration of Teachassist, a popular grade-viewing platform used by many high school students, Coursuccess provides an efficient way for students to check their current grades.

BxMCTF 2023

Feb 2023 - Jun 2023

BxMCTF 2023 is an international cybersecurity CTF (Capture the Flag) competition hosted by Bayview Cyber Security Club in collaboration with MGCI CTF Club. BxMCTF had over 3,500+ participants in 850+ teams from over 50+ countries around the globe. I contributed to problem-setting for the contest as well as logistics and project management.

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning with Python

IBM (International Business Machines)

Issued Jun 2023

Awarded for the completion of the IBM Machine Learning with Python course with a passing grade on the final exam.

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

freeCodeCamp

Issued Apr 2023

Awarded of the completion of the freeCodeCamp JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures course and receieved a passing grade on the final exam. The course also consisted of five projects/programs to be completed.

